

## **ABOUT ME**

My name is Matthew Callahan and I am a software engineer in Phoenix, Arizona. I have over ten years of experience in web and desktop software development using Scrum, Kanban, and XP agile methodologies. Learning the dynamic landscape of computer programming is my passion.

#### CONTACT

EMAIL:

matthew.callahan@outlook.com

PHONE:

630-988-1555

HOMEPAGE:

mfcallahan.com

LINKEDIN:

linkedin.com/in/mfcallahan1

GITHUB:

github.com/mfcallahan

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

Microsoft Technology Associate: Developer

# **KEY SKILLS**

C# (.NET & .NET Core)

JavaScript ES6+

TypeScript

Angular

Node.js

Python

Git

ArcGIS

Azure

# MATTHEW CALLAHAN

#### **EDUCATION**



University of Wisconsin–Madison Bachelor of Science, Geographic Information Systems

## **EXPERIENCE**

# Staff Engineer | Republic Services, Scottsdale, AZ | May 2019 - Present

- Lead a team of eight developers and testers, overseeing talent development, skill set improvement, and acting as a mentor to all team members.
- Established and implemented a standard application architecture for greenfield development (.NET & .NET Core back end/Angular front end).
- Implemented unit test standards for the team and led effort to increase test coverage on all apps, reducing the number of production bugs.
- Authored coding conventions and style guide documents for developers and currently leading effort to refactor all applications to follow these guidelines.
- Technologies used: .NET, .NET Core, C#, Angular, Node.js, TypeScript, JavaScript, Python, SQL Server, ArcGIS.

## Sr. Developer | Republic Services, Scottsdale, AZ | Dec 2018 - May 2019

- Developed enterprise GIS web applications which provided data mapping and route visualization tools to assist in business operations (ASP.NET, Angular).
- Developed APIs and services to deliver spatial data to teams and applications throughout the company (ASP.NET Web API).
- Supported desktop application development for GIS data analysis and batch data processing (ArcGIS Pro .NET SDK, Python).
- Implemented a uniform Git branching strategy and code review process for all application repositories.

#### Software Engineer | Carvana, Tempe, AZ | Feb 2018 - Dec 2018

- Primary job function was back end development to create and maintain the APIs and microservices which powered carvana.com (C#, .NET & .NET Core).
- Supported front end development to maintain and enhance a mobile responsive UI for a vehicle inventory search engine (|S ES6+, React/Redux, Angular|S).
- Implemented A/B testing to help drive data analytics and deliver the best UX.

## Application Developer | CBRE, Phoenix, AZ | Jan 2011 - Feb 2018

- Developed web applications which provided mapping and site selection data analysis tools for real estate brokers and their clients (ASP.NET MVC).
- Developed desktop applications for GIS data processing and analysis (C# .NET, WinForms, MapBasic, ArcGIS Pro .NET SDK, Python).
- Administered on-prem servers (Windows Server, IIS, SQL Server, ArcGIS Server).
- Employee of the year "MVP" award, 2012.

# GIS Technician | CBRE, Phoenix, AZ | Mar 2008 - Jan 2011

- Developed scripts and desktop GIS tools to automate tasks and improve workflow efficiency of GIS Technicians.
- Created custom maps, demographic reports, and market research reports for commercial real estate brokers, affording them the ability to make well informed decisions and best serve their clients.
- Employee of the Quarter, 1st quarter 2009.